<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Leadership on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</title>
    <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/tags/leadership/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Leadership on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Consortium of Ohio Libaries</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/cool-info/tags/leadership/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>EIC 2017</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Greater Cincinnati area, namely, Covington, KY, has been selected as the location for the 2017 Evergreen International Conference. The proposal was developed by Joe Knueven, director of the Germantown Public Library, and is a multi-state collaborative effort including the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, Asbury Theological Seminary (KY), Asbury University (KY), Kenton County Public Library (KY), and Evergreen Indiana. Knueven has also been named chair of the conference committee and will oversee the planning and implementation of the event. For more information about the Evergreen ILS, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://evergreen-ils.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://evergreen-ils.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floating in the Most Peculiar Way</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/floating/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/floating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago, COOL started floating collections between independently governed and funded libraries. The goal is to reduce wait times for patrons at member libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL libraries purchase multiple copies of items with high hold/copy ratios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items are processed without any local branding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items circulate throughout the consortium, without any geographic restrictions, on a “first in, first out” basis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once hold lists are fulfilled, the item resides where it was last returned and remains there until a hold from another library is generated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking at circulation numbers, it appears it is working as intended. Items with more than five holds per copy have reduced 12% since the project started. We only expect it to continue to improve as time goes on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Knueven, director of Germantown Public Library and Chauncey Montgomery, director of Community Library (Sunbury) will be doing a in-depth presentation of the project at the 2016 EIC conference in Raleigh, NC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
