<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</title>
    <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 Consortium of Ohio Libaries</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/cool-info/post/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>EIC 2017</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Greater Cincinnati area, namely, Covington, KY, has been selected as the location for the 2017 Evergreen International Conference. The proposal was developed by Joe Knueven, director of the Germantown Public Library, and is a multi-state collaborative effort including the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, Asbury Theological Seminary (KY), Asbury University (KY), Kenton County Public Library (KY), and Evergreen Indiana. Knueven has also been named chair of the conference committee and will oversee the planning and implementation of the event. For more information about the Evergreen ILS, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://evergreen-ils.org&#34;&gt;http://evergreen-ils.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floating in the Most Peculiar Way</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/floating/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/floating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago, COOL started floating collections between independently governed and funded libraries. The goal is to reduce wait times for patrons at member libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL libraries purchase multiple copies of items with high hold/copy ratios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items are processed without any local branding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items circulate throughout the consortium, without any geographic restrictions, on a “first in, first out” basis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once hold lists are fulfilled, the item resides where it was last returned and remains there until a hold from another library is generated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking at circulation numbers, it appears it is working as intended. Items with more than five holds per copy have reduced 12% since the project started. We only expect it to continue to improve as time goes on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Knueven, director of Germantown Public Library and Chauncey Montgomery, director of Community Library (Sunbury) will be doing a in-depth presentation of the project at the 2016 EIC conference in Raleigh, NC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authority Anyone?</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/authority/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest factors in having a successful catalog for your library or consortium is having good records!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, COOL has very recently partnered with Backstage Library Works (BSLW) and has instituted ongoing authority control for the catalog/database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/img/auth_control.png&#34; alt=&#34;image of a record&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ongoing, we will be loading both updated bibliographic records as well as authority records in an ongoing quarterly process.  At the same time, we’re instituting manual authority control procedures for locally created and eBook records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s certainly never easy, the end result will be a better catalog for both our patrons and staff!  If you have any questions for your library, drop us a line–we’ll be glad to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move to Sequoia</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/sequoia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/sequoia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 13, COOL moved to Sequoia. For more information, visit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://esilibrary.com/what-we-do/sequoia&#34;&gt;http://esilibrary.com/what-we-do/sequoia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to 2.7</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade2-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade2-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COOL will be upgrading to Evergreen 2.7 this December. The 2.7 version includes a Web-based staff interface that allows staff to turn any device with Internet access and a Web browser into a staff client. We will be able to perform circulation almost anywhere we need to with little effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in Ohio</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/ohio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/ohio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes Ohio such a great state to live in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out number eight:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movoto.com/oh/only-people-from-ohio-understand/&#34;&gt;http://www.movoto.com/oh/only-people-from-ohio-understand/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Boston!</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COOL members just returned from the 2014 Evergreen International Conference in Boston. It was such a great event. We built relationships with Evergreen users from all over the world, we discussed upcoming software features, and we improved our knowledge of the software. COOL also co-presented a tutorial on reporting and participated in a welcome panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/img/eic2014.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Evergreen Conference 2014&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events like this reiterate that Evergreen is more than just an ILS; it is a community of librarians, developers, etc., working together to build the best library experience ever. We’re all looking forward to the 2015 EIC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about Evergreen or COOL, please contact Lisa Murray at lmurray@cardlinc.org or Chauncey Montgomery at chauncey@yourcl.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Marvin</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/marvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/marvin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COOL would like to welcome Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby to COOL-CAT. On February 20, Marvin Memorial went live, bringing the total membership to eleven libraries with approximately 580,000 items in the system. To see a full list of members and a map of locations, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org/#member-libraries&#34;&gt;http://info.cool-cat.org/#member-libraries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio. If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please feel free to contact Lisa Murray, consortium chair at 419-864-8181 or lmurray@cardlinc.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL in Boston</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/img/econ2014.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Conference logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL will be representing Ohio libraries in two presentations at the 2014 Evergreen International Conference in Boston this March. One session is a tutorial on reports in Evergreen and the second is a panel discussion on migrating to Evergreen. To see a full list of programs, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://evergreen-ils.org/conference/eg14/schedule/&#34;&gt;http://evergreen-ils.org/conference/eg14/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome J. R. Clarke</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/jrclarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/jrclarke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/img/jrclarke-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;J.R. Clarke logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, J.R. Clarke Public Library in Covington went live in COOL-CAT, the shared catalog of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries. J. R. Clarke is the tenth library to migrate into the shared ILS since the consortium began in early 2012. COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To view J.R. Clarke’s catalog, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://jrclarke.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://jrclarke.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;. Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby will be migrating in early 2014. For more information about COOL, contact Chauncey Montgomery at 740-965-3901 or chauncey@yourcl.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL Receives Library Innovation Award</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/olcaward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/olcaward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the 2013 Ohio Library Council Convention and Expo, the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL) was awarded the Library Innovation Award for the planning and implementation of a statewide consortium using the open source ILS Evergreen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consortium was a response to the diminishing state funding. As funds decreased, libraries were forced to find ways to reduce costs while meeting the increased service demands. Joining a consortium was an obvious way to reduce costs by sharing support, hardware, and other administrative fees. A consortium also provides for seamless resource sharing between institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, COOL took the benefits of a consortium a step further and decided to use Evergreen, an open source ILS, because it provided a feature rich software package at a fraction of the cost of proprietary alternatives. Additionally, using open source software gives the consortium the ability to customize and add functionality based on individual needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/img/cool-directors.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;COOL Directors&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project kicked off in early 2012, when the consortium was awarded an LSTA grant from the State Library of Ohio. By March of 2012, Community Library (Sunbury) was migrated into COOL-CAT. Since then eight other libraries have migrated and two more are scheduled to join in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL would like to thank everyone that has made the project a success. OHIONET has been a solid partner throughout this whole project and COOL would not exist without their support. The State Library of Ohio is to be thanked for awarding the LSTA grant funds to get the project off the ground. The Evergreen community has been very kind and generous with their support as the consortium came together. Finally, COOL is thankful to the staff, trustees, and patrons that have supported us as we took on this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcanum Public Library Is Live</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/arcanum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/arcanum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, Arcanum Public Library went live in COOL-CAT, the shared catalog of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL). Arcanum is the ninth library in Ohio to migrate onto the system. J.R. Clarke Public Library and Marvin Memorial are the next two libraries scheduled to migrate later in 2013. To see a full list of members and a map of locations, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://info.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio. If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please feel free to contact consortium president, Chauncey Montgomery, at montgoc1@oplin.org or 740-965-3901, or Marilyn Walden, Director of Arcanum Public Library, waldenm1@oplin.org or 937-692-8484.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a COOL Spring!</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/cool-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/cool-spring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the weather is finally getting warmer, Ohio is getting a bit COOLer as two more libraries join the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL). COOL would like to welcome J.R. Clarke Public Library in Covington and Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby as its newest members to the consortium. Both libraries voted to join COOL at their May meetings. J.R. Clarke plans to migrate into COOL-CAT later this summer and Marvin Memorial is planning on migrating in the fall. They will be the 10th and 11th libraries in consortium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL is a consortium managed and governed by a community of libraries, using the open source ILS, Evergreen. Technical support is provided by OHIONET in Columbus. For a current list of member libraries, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://info.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;. For information about Evergreen, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.open-ils.org&#34;&gt;http://www.open-ils.org&lt;/a&gt;. Please contact Chauncey Montgomery at 740-965-3901 or montgoc1@oplin.org for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chair of COOL Elected to Evergreen Oversight Board</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/oversight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/oversight/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;During the recent Evergreen conference in Vancouver, four newly elected members to the Evergreen Oversight Board were announced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Board is the executive team of the Evergreen software project that makes guiding decisions and leads the project forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-goal-of-the-board-is-to&#34;&gt;The goal of the Board is to :&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Promote, support, and advance the development of the Evergreen software;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Support and facilitate the growth of the international community of Evergreen users; and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Foster and protect the Evergreen assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-members&#34;&gt;Current Members:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shauna Borger, Indiana State Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Galen Charlton, Equinox Software, Inc. Chair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stephen Elfstrand, MnPALS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rogan Hamby, York County Library (South Carolina) and SC LENDS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ben Hyman, British Columbia Libraries Cooperative Vice Chair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kathy Lussier, Massachusetts Library Network Cooperative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elizabeth McKinney, Georgia Public Library Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chauncey Montgomery, Sunbury Community Library (Ohio)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrea Bunz Neiman, Kent County Public Library (Maryland)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yamil Suarez, Berklee College of Music&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stephen Wills, Beyond Print&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL to Present at Evergreen International Conference in Vancouver, B.C.</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2013/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Tony Bandy of OHIONET and Chauncey Montgomery of Community Library (Sunbury) will be representing Ohio at the upcoming Evergreen International Conference in Vancouver. They will be presenting a session at the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;following-is-a-brief-description-of-their-session&#34;&gt;Following is a brief description of their session:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Evergreen continues to grow and innovate, more and more libraries and library consortium’s are moving to this amazing ILS system. However, for standalone libraries or newly formed consortiums, circulation within the system is a whole new game! From workflow to holds policies and those crazily-configured circulation rules, it takes both time and understanding to come to grips with the change. Given this, plan on taking this quick and enlightening tour of 5 themes you need to consider when implementing your library on an Evergreen consortium-level platform!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the full schedule and more information, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://eg2013.sitka.bclibraries.ca/schedule/&#34;&gt;http://eg2013.sitka.bclibraries.ca/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
