<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</title>
    <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Consortium of Ohio Libaries</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to Release 3.1</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade3-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade3-1/</guid>
      <description>On August 23, COOL upgraded to the 3.1 release of Evergreen. New features include search term highlighting in the public catalog and the ability to place multiple holds at once. This feature is extremely beneficial for book clubs and reading groups that need to place holds on multiple copies of a title.
The Consortium of Ohio Libraries contributed funding for the development of search term highlighting and indexing improvements to improve performance of keyword searches.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Due Date Reminders</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/sms-reminders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/sms-reminders/</guid>
      <description>On Monday June 11th, COOL implemented a new SMS courtesy notification service for patrons. A text message reminder will be sent out 3 days prior to the due date of any circulating item. Patrons must opt-in to receiving SMS notifications, as well as have an SMS text number and carrier declared in their accounts to take advantage of this new notification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL Welcomes Galion Public Library</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/galion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/galion/</guid>
      <description>Galion Public Library joined COOL today, adding over 97,000 items to the COOL-CAT collection. We are very excited to have Galion in our group. Galion Public Library is the 12th library to join COOL since its inception in 2012. COOL is always open to new members. If you are interested becoming a COOL library, or if you want more information on the consortium or Evergreen, contact Matt Polcyn, Director of Technology Services at OhioNET, at mattp@ohionet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcanum Goes Fine Fee!</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/finefree/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/finefree/</guid>
      <description>Beginning April 1st, Arcanum Public Library patrons will no longer receives fines for overdue items. To be sure materials are still returned, the library will be imposing fees on items that are lost, damaged, or not returned 30 days past the due date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to Release 3.0</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade3-0/</guid>
      <description>On January 10, COOL became the first consortium on the Sequoia platform to upgrade to the 3.0 release of Evergreen. New features include the ability to batch edit patron records and the ability to send text message notifications to patrons 3 days prior to the due date of any circulting material. Release 3.0 initiates the transition from the XUL staff client to a web-based staff client for all Evergreen modules, including serials and acquisitions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL Leadership for 2018</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/elections2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/elections2017/</guid>
      <description>Elections were held during the December meeting of the COOL Directors. Congratulations to our new leaders!
 Meme Marlow, Worch Memorial Public Library, Chair Joe Knueven, Germantown Public Library, Vice Chair Kathleen Webb, Marvin Memorial Public Library, Secretary  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RightClick 2017</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/rightclick2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/rightclick2017/</guid>
      <description>Two representatives from the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, Joe Knueven, Director of Germantown Public Library, and Derek Zoladz, Project Coordinator for the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, will be speaking at RightClick: The Library IT Idea Exchange Conference. Sponsored by the Ohio Library Councel&amp;rsquo;s Information Technology Division, this one-day conference for IT professionals, administrators and support staff will be held at the State Library of Ohio in downtown Columbus.
Here are the summaries for each presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIC 2017</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2017/</guid>
      <description>The Greater Cincinnati area, namely, Covington, KY, has been selected as the location for the 2017 Evergreen International Conference. The proposal was developed by Joe Knueven, director of the Germantown Public Library, and is a multi-state collaborative effort including the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, Asbury Theological Seminary (KY), Asbury University (KY), Kenton County Public Library (KY), and Evergreen Indiana. Knueven has also been named chair of the conference committee and will oversee the planning and implementation of the event.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floating in the Most Peculiar Way</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/floating/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/floating/</guid>
      <description>A couple months ago, COOL started floating collections between independently governed and funded libraries. The goal is to reduce wait times for patrons at member libraries.
Here’s how it works:
 COOL libraries purchase multiple copies of items with high hold/copy ratios. Items are processed without any local branding. Items circulate throughout the consortium, without any geographic restrictions, on a “first in, first out” basis. Once hold lists are fulfilled, the item resides where it was last returned and remains there until a hold from another library is generated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authority Anyone?</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/authority/</guid>
      <description>One of the biggest factors in having a successful catalog for your library or consortium is having good records!
With this in mind, COOL has very recently partnered with Backstage Library Works (BSLW) and has instituted ongoing authority control for the catalog/database.
Ongoing, we will be loading both updated bibliographic records as well as authority records in an ongoing quarterly process. At the same time, we’re instituting manual authority control procedures for locally created and eBook records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move to Sequoia</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/sequoia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/sequoia/</guid>
      <description>On January 13, COOL moved to Sequoia. For more information, visit: http://esilibrary.com/what-we-do/sequoia</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to 2.7</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade2-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade2-7/</guid>
      <description>COOL will be upgrading to Evergreen 2.7 this December. The 2.7 version includes a Web-based staff interface that allows staff to turn any device with Internet access and a Web browser into a staff client. We will be able to perform circulation almost anywhere we need to with little effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in Ohio</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/ohio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/ohio/</guid>
      <description>What makes Ohio such a great state to live in?
Check out number eight: http://www.movoto.com/oh/only-people-from-ohio-understand/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Boston!</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston2/</guid>
      <description>COOL members just returned from the 2014 Evergreen International Conference in Boston. It was such a great event. We built relationships with Evergreen users from all over the world, we discussed upcoming software features, and we improved our knowledge of the software. COOL also co-presented a tutorial on reporting and participated in a welcome panel.
Events like this reiterate that Evergreen is more than just an ILS; it is a community of librarians, developers, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Marvin</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/marvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/marvin/</guid>
      <description>COOL would like to welcome Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby to COOL-CAT. On February 20, Marvin Memorial went live, bringing the total membership to eleven libraries with approximately 580,000 items in the system. To see a full list of members and a map of locations, go to http://info.cool-cat.org/#member-libraries.
COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio. If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please feel free to contact Lisa Murray, consortium chair at 419-864-8181 or lmurray@cardlinc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL in Boston</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston/</guid>
      <description>COOL will be representing Ohio libraries in two presentations at the 2014 Evergreen International Conference in Boston this March. One session is a tutorial on reports in Evergreen and the second is a panel discussion on migrating to Evergreen. To see a full list of programs, go to http://evergreen-ils.org/conference/eg14/schedule/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome J. R. Clarke</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/jrclarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/jrclarke/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday, J.R. Clarke Public Library in Covington went live in COOL-CAT, the shared catalog of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries. J. R. Clarke is the tenth library to migrate into the shared ILS since the consortium began in early 2012. COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio.
To view J.R. Clarke’s catalog, visit http://jrclarke.cool-cat.org. Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby will be migrating in early 2014.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL Receives Library Innovation Award</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/olcaward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/olcaward/</guid>
      <description>At the 2013 Ohio Library Council Convention and Expo, the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL) was awarded the Library Innovation Award for the planning and implementation of a statewide consortium using the open source ILS Evergreen.
The consortium was a response to the diminishing state funding. As funds decreased, libraries were forced to find ways to reduce costs while meeting the increased service demands. Joining a consortium was an obvious way to reduce costs by sharing support, hardware, and other administrative fees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcanum Public Library Is Live</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/arcanum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/arcanum/</guid>
      <description>Today, Arcanum Public Library went live in COOL-CAT, the shared catalog of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL). Arcanum is the ninth library in Ohio to migrate onto the system. J.R. Clarke Public Library and Marvin Memorial are the next two libraries scheduled to migrate later in 2013. To see a full list of members and a map of locations, go to http://info.cool-cat.org.
COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a COOL Spring!</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/cool-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/cool-spring/</guid>
      <description>Although the weather is finally getting warmer, Ohio is getting a bit COOLer as two more libraries join the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL). COOL would like to welcome J.R. Clarke Public Library in Covington and Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby as its newest members to the consortium. Both libraries voted to join COOL at their May meetings. J.R. Clarke plans to migrate into COOL-CAT later this summer and Marvin Memorial is planning on migrating in the fall.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chair of COOL Elected to Evergreen Oversight Board</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/oversight/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/oversight/</guid>
      <description>During the recent Evergreen conference in Vancouver, four newly elected members to the Evergreen Oversight Board were announced.
The Board is the executive team of the Evergreen software project that makes guiding decisions and leads the project forward.
The goal of the Board is to :  Promote, support, and advance the development of the Evergreen software; Support and facilitate the growth of the international community of Evergreen users; and Foster and protect the Evergreen assets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL to Present at Evergreen International Conference in Vancouver, B.C.</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2013/</guid>
      <description>Tony Bandy of OHIONET and Chauncey Montgomery of Community Library (Sunbury) will be representing Ohio at the upcoming Evergreen International Conference in Vancouver. They will be presenting a session at the conference.
Following is a brief description of their session: While Evergreen continues to grow and innovate, more and more libraries and library consortium’s are moving to this amazing ILS system. However, for standalone libraries or newly formed consortiums, circulation within the system is a whole new game!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two More Libraries Live in COOL</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/two-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/two-live/</guid>
      <description>COOL would like to officially welcome Blanchester Public Library and Wornstaff Memorial Public Library in Ashley to COOL-CAT. Today, March 14, the two libraries went live, bringing the total to eight libraries with approximately 390,000 items in the system.
It is hard to believe, but it was just a year ago that Community Library in Sunbury kicked COOL off. With the help and expertise of OHIONET and financial support from an LSTA grant awarded by the State Library of Ohio, COOL has been able to maintain its aggressive migration timeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blanchester Public Library becomes COOL March 14</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/blanchester/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/blanchester/</guid>
      <description>The Blanchester Public Library will be closed to the public Thursday, March 14, as it is scheduled to go live on the Evergreen shared catalog as part of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL).
Library patrons are strongly encouraged to have their library cards with them to check out materials beginning March 11 as staff members will have limited access to account information during the week. Patrons also will not be able to access their account or the current online catalog until the new system is in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worch goes live with COOL!</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/worch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/worch/</guid>
      <description>Today, the Worch Memorial Public Library went live with Evergreen on the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL) shared catalog.
Worch Memorial is sixth of the nine founding members to migrate onto the system, with an estimated final library migration into the consortium scheduled for August 2013. Please visit the information site for more details about the Consortium, or take a look at the new catalog for Worch directly: http://worch.cool-cat.org.
COOL is running on the open source ILS Evergreen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Survey Results</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/survey/</guid>
      <description>A user survey was completed before and after migration to assess how user-friendly Evergreen is compared to previous systems. Participants were asked to rate how easy it was to complete basic tasks in the catalog. Responses ranged on a scale from “very easy” to “very difficult” Following is a list of tasks with the percentage of respondents that answered “very easy” and “easy”.
   Task Legacy System Evergreen     Find a specific title.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL-CAT to Upgrade</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade2-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade2-3/</guid>
      <description>On November 18, COOL-CAT will be upgraded to Evergreen 2.3. The upgrade includes a major overhaul of the public catalog. New features will include a simpler interface, auto-complete, and loan history, among others. The new catalog is also much lighter than the traditional OPAC, so it should be faster. The staff client also has some new features. For more information, go to http://evergreen-ils.org/blog/?p=818. We are all looking forward to the upgrade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Are Live</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/five-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/five-live/</guid>
      <description>On August 9th, Mt. Gilead Public Library and Cardington-Lincoln Public Library went live in COOL-CAT. Mt. Gilead and Cardington-Lincoln are the fourth and fifth libraries to migrate into the system. They join Community Library (Sunbury), Germantown Public Library, and Selover Public Library that migrated to COOL-CAT earlier this year.
COOL-CAT is the shared Evergreen catalog of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries. It is hosted and administered by OHIONET in conjunction with the member libraries and funded in part through an Institute of Museum and Library Services LSTA grant awarded by the State Library of Ohio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats have nine lives, COOL-CAT has nine libraries</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/nine-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/nine-lives/</guid>
      <description>The Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL) is pleased to announce that Arcanum Public Library will be joining the consortium. Arcanum will be the ninth library in the consortium. Migration of the collection and users into COOL-CAT will take place sometime in spring 2013.
COOL currently consists of Blanchester Public Library, Cardington-Lincoln Public Library, Community Library, Germantown Public Library, Mt. Gilead Public Library, Selover Public Library, Worch Memorial Public Library, Wornstaff Memorial Library, and now Arcanum Public Library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot News for Selover Public Library</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/selover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/selover/</guid>
      <description>On Tuesday, June 5th, the Selover Public Library went live with Evergreen on the Consortium of Ohio Libraries shared catalog, COOL-CAT.
COOL is made up of independent libraries that are striving to provide innovative library services while being more efficient with diminishing public resources. Selover is the third of eight libraries that are tagged to be added in the next few months. Members currently in COOL-CAT are Community Library in Sunbury, Germantown Public Library and Selover Public Library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Germantown goes live with COOL!</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/germantown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/germantown/</guid>
      <description>Today the Germantown Public Library went live with Evergreen on the Consortium of Ohio Libraries shared catalog.
Evergreen is the open source ILS originally developed in Georgia and now in use by over 200 libraries in 22 states, and in 6 other countries. This count only includes reported installations, as anybody is free to download and install the software and try it out for themselves.
The Consortium of Ohio Libraries is a new consortium funded in part by an LSTA grant and supported by OHIONET in Columbus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL @ Evergreen International Conference</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2012/</guid>
      <description>Representatives from COOL libraries and OHIONET recently attended the 2012 Evergreen International Conference in Indianapolis. It was an excellent event and featured keynote speakers Jano Bacon, a leading community manager, engineering manager, consultant, and author, and Galadriel Chilton, Electronic Resource Management Librarian at University of Connecticut. Many of the sessions focused on future developments in Evergreen, especially features coming in version 2.2.
Many features will benefit patrons, such as auto-suggest, SMS, patron history (loans, fines, and holds), etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results of Migration to Evergreen: Crash &amp; Burn?</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/migration/</guid>
      <description>Migration went briefly like this: First: COOL consortium was formed with Principles of Cooperation, etc. A worthy item of note: you pretty much keep your own song sheet. Do, or don’t, charge for overdue books, have a special fine structure, etc. ? Your call.
Next: Pre-work before the migration. 4 1&amp;frasl;2 days (last week of January) introductory training at OhioNET, for various staff on certain days. Consortium and migration meetings and conference calls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL-CAT Is Live</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/were-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/were-live/</guid>
      <description>The Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL) is pleased to announce that the migration of the first library in the consortium is complete and the catalog, COOL-CAT, is live, purring, and available for patrons of the Community Library in Sunbury to locate items.
Following this initial migration, the Germantown Public Library will be joining in May of this year, followed by libraries in Chesterville, Cardington and Mt. Gilead at the end of summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LSTA Funds COOL</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/lsta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/lsta/</guid>
      <description>A group of libraries was recently awarded a $108,092 Library Service Technology Act grant by the State Library of Ohio to fund the initial formation of Ohio’s first Evergreen consortium. Consisting of eight libraries, the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL) has partnered with OHIONET in Columbus, Ohio, to oversee migration and support.
Funds awarded will assist four libraries with the initial installation, configuration, and migration to the open source ILS, Evergreen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>