<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Members on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</title>
    <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/tags/members/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Members on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Consortium of Ohio Libaries</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/members/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Marvin</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/marvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/marvin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COOL would like to welcome Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby to COOL-CAT. On February 20, Marvin Memorial went live, bringing the total membership to eleven libraries with approximately 580,000 items in the system. To see a full list of members and a map of locations, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org/#member-libraries&#34;&gt;http://info.cool-cat.org/#member-libraries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio. If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please feel free to contact Lisa Murray, consortium chair at 419-864-8181 or lmurray@cardlinc.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome J. R. Clarke</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/jrclarke/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/jrclarke/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org/img/jrclarke-logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;J.R. Clarke logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, J.R. Clarke Public Library in Covington went live in COOL-CAT, the shared catalog of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries. J. R. Clarke is the tenth library to migrate into the shared ILS since the consortium began in early 2012. COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To view J.R. Clarke’s catalog, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://jrclarke.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://jrclarke.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;. Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby will be migrating in early 2014. For more information about COOL, contact Chauncey Montgomery at 740-965-3901 or chauncey@yourcl.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL Receives Library Innovation Award</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/olcaward/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/olcaward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the 2013 Ohio Library Council Convention and Expo, the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL) was awarded the Library Innovation Award for the planning and implementation of a statewide consortium using the open source ILS Evergreen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The consortium was a response to the diminishing state funding. As funds decreased, libraries were forced to find ways to reduce costs while meeting the increased service demands. Joining a consortium was an obvious way to reduce costs by sharing support, hardware, and other administrative fees. A consortium also provides for seamless resource sharing between institutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, COOL took the benefits of a consortium a step further and decided to use Evergreen, an open source ILS, because it provided a feature rich software package at a fraction of the cost of proprietary alternatives. Additionally, using open source software gives the consortium the ability to customize and add functionality based on individual needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org/img/cool-directors.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;COOL Directors&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project kicked off in early 2012, when the consortium was awarded an LSTA grant from the State Library of Ohio. By March of 2012, Community Library (Sunbury) was migrated into COOL-CAT. Since then eight other libraries have migrated and two more are scheduled to join in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL would like to thank everyone that has made the project a success. OHIONET has been a solid partner throughout this whole project and COOL would not exist without their support. The State Library of Ohio is to be thanked for awarding the LSTA grant funds to get the project off the ground. The Evergreen community has been very kind and generous with their support as the consortium came together. Finally, COOL is thankful to the staff, trustees, and patrons that have supported us as we took on this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arcanum Public Library Is Live</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/arcanum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/arcanum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, Arcanum Public Library went live in COOL-CAT, the shared catalog of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL). Arcanum is the ninth library in Ohio to migrate onto the system. J.R. Clarke Public Library and Marvin Memorial are the next two libraries scheduled to migrate later in 2013. To see a full list of members and a map of locations, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://info.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio. If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please feel free to contact consortium president, Chauncey Montgomery, at montgoc1@oplin.org or 740-965-3901, or Marilyn Walden, Director of Arcanum Public Library, waldenm1@oplin.org or 937-692-8484.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What a COOL Spring!</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/cool-spring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2013 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/cool-spring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Although the weather is finally getting warmer, Ohio is getting a bit COOLer as two more libraries join the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL). COOL would like to welcome J.R. Clarke Public Library in Covington and Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby as its newest members to the consortium. Both libraries voted to join COOL at their May meetings. J.R. Clarke plans to migrate into COOL-CAT later this summer and Marvin Memorial is planning on migrating in the fall. They will be the 10th and 11th libraries in consortium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL is a consortium managed and governed by a community of libraries, using the open source ILS, Evergreen. Technical support is provided by OHIONET in Columbus. For a current list of member libraries, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://info.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;. For information about Evergreen, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.open-ils.org&#34;&gt;http://www.open-ils.org&lt;/a&gt;. Please contact Chauncey Montgomery at 740-965-3901 or montgoc1@oplin.org for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL to Present at Evergreen International Conference in Vancouver, B.C.</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/eic-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/eic-2013/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Tony Bandy of OHIONET and Chauncey Montgomery of Community Library (Sunbury) will be representing Ohio at the upcoming Evergreen International Conference in Vancouver. They will be presenting a session at the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;following-is-a-brief-description-of-their-session&#34;&gt;Following is a brief description of their session:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Evergreen continues to grow and innovate, more and more libraries and library consortium’s are moving to this amazing ILS system. However, for standalone libraries or newly formed consortiums, circulation within the system is a whole new game! From workflow to holds policies and those crazily-configured circulation rules, it takes both time and understanding to come to grips with the change. Given this, plan on taking this quick and enlightening tour of 5 themes you need to consider when implementing your library on an Evergreen consortium-level platform!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the full schedule and more information, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://eg2013.sitka.bclibraries.ca/schedule/&#34;&gt;http://eg2013.sitka.bclibraries.ca/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two More Libraries Live in COOL</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/two-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2013 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/two-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COOL would like to officially welcome Blanchester Public Library and Wornstaff Memorial Public Library in Ashley to COOL-CAT. Today, March 14, the two libraries went live, bringing the total to eight libraries with approximately 390,000 items in the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is hard to believe, but it was just a year ago that Community Library in Sunbury kicked COOL off. With the help and expertise of OHIONET and financial support from an LSTA grant awarded by the State Library of Ohio, COOL has been able to maintain its aggressive migration timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to have these two libraries on board. Arcanum Public Library will be migrating into COOL-CAT this August.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blanchester Public Library becomes COOL March 14</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/blanchester/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2013 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/blanchester/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Blanchester Public Library will be closed to the public Thursday, March 14, as it is scheduled to go live on the Evergreen shared catalog as part of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Library patrons are strongly encouraged to have their library cards with them to check out materials beginning March 11 as staff members will have limited access to account information during the week. Patrons also will not be able to access their account or the current online catalog until the new system is in place. No overdue fines will be incurred during this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library is one of nine founding members of COOL, which was formed in 2012. The consortium consists of independent libraries striving to provide innovative services while being more efficient with diminishing public resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joining the consortium will give library cardholders quick access to more than 400,000 items held by the consortium’s libraries. Items at other COOL libraries will be easily requestable in the catalog and should be available for pickup at Blanchester Public Library within a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to the Evergreen platform also puts the library in the forefront of the open source movement and gives it much more of a voice in the development of the product compared to the current product from a commercial vendor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evergreen was developed by several public libraries in Georgia in 2006 and is now used by more than 1,000 libraries, including most of the public libraries in Indiana, several in South Carolina, and by one of the largest public libraries in the United States, the King County Library System in Washington. The COOL catalog is hosted and administered by OHIONET in conjunction with the member libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other current COOL members are Cardington-Lincoln Public Library, Community Library in Sunbury, Germantown Public Library, Mt. Gilead Public Library, Selover Public Library, Worch Memorial Public Library, Wornstaff Memorial Library, and Arcanum Public Library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library will re-open at 10 a.m., Friday, March. 15. For more information, contact the Blanchester Public Library at (937) 783-3585.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worch goes live with COOL!</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/worch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2013 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/worch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, the Worch Memorial Public Library went live with Evergreen on the Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL) shared catalog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Worch Memorial is sixth of the nine founding members to migrate onto the system, with an estimated final library migration into the consortium scheduled for August 2013. Please visit the information site for more details about the Consortium, or take a look at the new catalog for Worch directly:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://worch.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://worch.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL is running on the open source ILS Evergreen. Originally developed by PINES (Public Information Network for Electronic Services) for the Georgia Public Library Service, Evergreen has since grown and is now used by over 1,000 libraries across 31 states, 4 countries, and 8 Canadian provinces. This count only includes reported installations, as anybody is free to download, install and try it out for their library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please feel free to contact consortium president Chauncey Montgomery, Director of the Community Library in Sunbury (montgoc1@oplin.org or 740-965-3901), or Meme Marlow, Director of the Worch Memorial Public Library, (marlowme@oplin.org or 937-526-3416).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>User Survey Results</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/survey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A user survey was completed before and after migration to assess how user-friendly Evergreen is compared to previous systems. Participants were asked to rate how easy it was to complete basic tasks in the catalog. Responses ranged on a scale from “very easy” to “very difficult” Following is a list of tasks with the percentage of respondents that answered “very easy” and “easy”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Task&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Legacy System&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;Evergreen&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Find a specific title.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;80%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;95%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Find titles based on a subject search.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;65%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;78%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Limit searches to a specific collection.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;41%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;56%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Understand the search results.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;76%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;77%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Place an item on hold.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;88%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;91%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Add items to a list or bookbag.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;38%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;79%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Access account information.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;73%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;92%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Renew items.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;90%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;87%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;left&#34;&gt;Request an item from another library.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;50%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td align=&#34;center&#34;&gt;91%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all categories, with the exception of renewing items, ease-of-use increased in Evergreen. It is also worth noting that the survey was completed just a month after migration, so this represents going from systems that had been in place for years to a new system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also worth noting that the survey was completed when we were still on Evergreen 2.1. We are now running Evergreen 2.3, which has a much more intuitive OPAC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Are Live</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/five-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/five-live/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On August 9th, Mt. Gilead Public Library and Cardington-Lincoln Public Library went live in COOL-CAT. Mt. Gilead and Cardington-Lincoln are the fourth and fifth libraries to migrate into the system. They join Community Library (Sunbury), Germantown Public Library, and Selover Public Library that migrated to COOL-CAT earlier this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL-CAT is the shared Evergreen catalog of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries. It is hosted and administered by OHIONET in conjunction with the member libraries and funded in part through an Institute of Museum and Library Services LSTA grant awarded by the State Library of Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://info.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;, or take a look at the catalog directly at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://www.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;. Also, feel free to contact consortium president Chauncey Montgomery, Director of the Community Library (montgoc1@oplin.org or 740-965-3901) or Tony Bandy, Technology Specialist at OHIONET (tonyb@ohionet.org or 800-686-8975, ext. 19).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cats have nine lives, COOL-CAT has nine libraries</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/nine-lives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jun 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/nine-lives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL) is pleased to announce that Arcanum Public Library will be joining the consortium. Arcanum will be the ninth library in the consortium.  Migration of the collection and users into COOL-CAT will take place sometime in spring 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL currently consists of Blanchester Public Library, Cardington-Lincoln Public Library, Community Library, Germantown Public Library, Mt. Gilead Public Library, Selover Public Library, Worch Memorial Public Library, Wornstaff Memorial Library, and now Arcanum Public Library.  COOL uses Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is funded in part by an LSTA grant and supported by OHIONET in Columbus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about COOL, please contact Chauncey Montgomery at 740-965-3901 or montgoc1@oplin.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot News for Selover Public Library</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/selover/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/selover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday, June 5th, the Selover Public Library went live with Evergreen on the Consortium of Ohio Libraries shared catalog, COOL-CAT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL is made up of independent libraries that are striving to provide innovative library services while being more efficient with diminishing public resources. Selover is the third of eight libraries that are tagged to be added in the next few months. Members currently in COOL-CAT are Community Library in Sunbury, Germantown Public Library and Selover Public Library. The next libraries scheduled to migrate are Cardington Public Library and Mt. Gilead Public Library in August 2012.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Selover is excited and pleased with the transition to the COOL-CAT, it provides easier access to a much larger collection of library materials. Joining the consortium also allows greater convenience for library patrons who can now pick up and drop off materials at several local libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evergreen, the open source ILS originally developed by PINES (Public Information Network for Electronic Services) for the Georgia Public Library Service, is used by over 1,000 libraries across 31 states, 4 countries, and 8 Canadian provinces. This count only includes reported installations, as anybody is free to download, install and try it out for their library. The new Consortium of Ohio Libraries, initially funded by an LSTA grant and local library funding, is hosted and administered by OHIONET in conjunction with the member libraries. Take
a look at the catalog directly at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cool-cat.org&#34;&gt;http://www.cool-cat.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please feel free to contact me at Selover Public Library, lylesu@oplin.org 419-768-343l or contact the consortium’s president Chauncey Montgomery, Director of the Community Library in Sunbury montgoc1@oplin.org 740-965-390l. Tony Bandy is the Technology Specialist at OHIONET in charge of supporting COOL. He is also available to answer questions about the consortium at tonyb@ohionet.org or 800-686-8975, ext. 19.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Germantown goes live with COOL!</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/germantown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2012 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/germantown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the Germantown Public Library went live with Evergreen on the Consortium of Ohio Libraries shared catalog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evergreen is the open source ILS originally developed in Georgia and now in use by over 200 libraries in 22 states, and in 6 other countries. This count only includes reported installations, as anybody is free to download and install the software and try it out for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Consortium of Ohio Libraries is a new consortium funded in part by an LSTA grant and supported by OHIONET in Columbus. Germantown is the second of the eight founding members to migrate onto the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please feel free to contact Joe Knueven, director of Germantown, at 937-696-9998, ext. 10, or knuevejo@oplin.org or contacting the consortium’s president, Chauncey Montgomery, Director of the Community Library in Sunbury. He may be reached at 740-965-3901 or montgoc1@oplin.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Results of Migration to Evergreen: Crash &amp; Burn?</title>
      <link>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 13:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://info.cool-cat.org/post/migration/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;migration-went-briefly-like-this&#34;&gt;Migration went briefly like this:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First: COOL consortium was formed with Principles of Cooperation, etc.
A worthy item of note: you pretty much keep your own song sheet.
Do, or don’t, charge for overdue books, have a special fine structure, etc. ? Your call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;next-pre-work-before-the-migration&#34;&gt;Next: Pre-work before the migration.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; days (last week of January) introductory training at OhioNET, for various staff on certain days.
Consortium and migration meetings and conference calls.
Data cleanup and addition collection weeding.
Test data extracts &amp;amp; analyzing. Data map assignments. Lending, fee, etc. policies.
Etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The technical work (my area) inside the library was a piece of cake.
Opened a port for a certain IP access through the firewall, to our server.
Verified Remote Desktop was enabled on the server.
Installed the Evergreen client on 15 workstations at about 3-5 minutes each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finally-actual-migration-and-switch-to-evergreen&#34;&gt;Finally: Actual migration and switch to Evergreen.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday, Tuesday, &amp;amp; Wednesday (March 12, 13, &amp;amp; 14)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used Evergreen Offline Mode for checkout only.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Returned items went on carts, shelves, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patron and item data migrated to Evergreen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday March 18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library closed to the public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chauncey Montgomery (Director) gave training presentation with hands-on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday March 16&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library closed to the public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More hands-on in the morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Afternoon the staff checked in accumulated items with Evergreen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saturday March 17&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library closed to the public&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone (except maybe Chauncey and Joni) took the day off.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sunday March 18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always closed on Sunday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monday March 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open for business just like normal but running Evergreen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few glitches but nobody quit and patrons were satisfied.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this week OhioNet and Equinox fine-tuned the migration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been relatively minor (no show stopper) issues to address. I’d elaborate but have no clue, as not my area of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-d-we-do-it&#34;&gt;Why’d we do it?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Years and years ago we heard about Koha, so visited Nelsonville Library and did a cold call on Joshua Ferraro at LibLime.
Also a visit to Stow-Munroe Falls Public Library.
Koha seemed very good, but we decided Liblime was too much money for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Jo Budler held State Library meetings on Evergreen, we started following it’s development.
Eric Maynard’s Functional Comparison to Horizon was very thorough and helpful.
Evergreen features, phenomenal growth and the backing of major library systems really sold us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I personally envisioned a state data center running Evergreen.
No longer would every library need a new server, s/w upgrades, backup solution, etc. every 3 to 5 years.
Duplicate ILS vendor support, upgrade and h/w cost would be reduced.
Libraries could share these reduced costs saving money.
So those bushel baskets of $$$ libraries yearly send out of state (to ILS vendors) remain in Ohio
(All this would look good to the state legislature at budget time)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(But best was, offsite program and data storage. No more circ backup worries ! Yesss!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;some-benefit-to-community-library-and-patrons&#34;&gt;Some benefit to Community Library and Patrons&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A feature rich ILS, library driven and continually improving.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seamless consortium resource sharing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offsite servers and internet professionally managed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduced long term cost providing more money for acquisitions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;thank-you-s-to-the-groups-making-migration-possible&#34;&gt;Thank you’s to the groups making migration possible&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OhioNet for vision. overall guidance and support, excellent project supervision, Tier I support, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;State Library of Ohio LSTA grant award to the COOL Consortium.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL Consortium libraries for their vision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Equinox for migration support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library staff for adoption to change and overall support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BTW Most, if not everything, is my thoughts and opinions. And, your mileage may vary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Bob Neeper&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
