<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Consortium of Ohio Libraries on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</title>
    <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Consortium of Ohio Libraries on Consortium of Ohio Libraries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018 Consortium of Ohio Libaries</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/cool-info/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Bylaws</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/policy/bylaws/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Apr 2018 14:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/policy/bylaws/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;name-and-mission&#34;&gt;NAME AND MISSION&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Name of this organization shall be Consortium of Ohio Libraries (COOL).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mission of the Consortium of Ohio Libraries is to meet the information needs of Ohioans through the cooperation of independent libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;membership&#34;&gt;MEMBERSHIP&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Members. There shall be one class of membership in COOL. Membership is held by the participating library. Each member library is a voting member with one vote on the Executive Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Qualifications. Membership shall be limited to any tax-payer funded library in Ohio that provides library services and offers a collection for loan beyond its district of service according to the policies and procedures established by COOL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Application for Membership. Prospective members may apply to join COOL by submitting a completed COOL Membership Agreement form to the Chair of the Executive Board. The Executive Board shall vote on all prospective membership applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Term. Membership shall be on a calendar year (January 1 – December 31), effective upon receipt of a signed COOL Membership Agreement. Membership is automatically renewed on an annual basis unless notification of termination is given as described in item 5, “Termination”, below.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Termination. Any member library can terminate membership in COOL by providing written notice to the Chair of the Executive Board as stated in the COOL Membership Agreement. Notice to terminate membership must be received 12 months before termination. The Executive Board may, by two-thirds (&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) majority of all Executive Board representatives, terminate a membership whenever in its judgment the best interests of COOL would be served.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database. A member library entity leaving COOL or being terminated has the right to receive at cost with in six months a complete copy of its database with attached bibliographic records and patron records extracted from the COOL database in a format meeting the library’s needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working Groups. All member libraries will make available personnel to serve on any working group the Executive Board deems necessary to support COOL. Libraries that cannot assign a member to every working group agree to abide by the policies developed by the working groups and approved by the Executive Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-board&#34;&gt;EXECUTIVE BOARD&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number and Term. All participating libraries will have a seat on the Executive Board filled by the director or a designee. Once membership in COOL reaches 20 members, the Executive Board will re-examine the structure of COOL governance with an eye toward making it a representative council with members appointed for two-year terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Officers. The Executive Board shall elect the following officers: Chair, Vice-chair, and Secretary.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officers&amp;rsquo; Duties. The Chair, Vice-chair, and Secretary will perform the following duties and may perform other duties as assigned by the Executive Board:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Chair

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Preside over all COOL Executive Board meetings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Serve as public spokesperson for COOL.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prepare and distribute an agenda at least three business days prior to each regular Executive Board meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Represent COOL in consortium contracts executed and administered by OHIONET.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vice-chair

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assume the authority and responsibilities of Chair in the Chair&amp;rsquo;s absence or unavailability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Become Chair the following term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigate and present to the Executive Board any grievance from a COOL library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Past-chair

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seat occupied by previous chair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide continuity and historical perspective to consortial leadership.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Secretary

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain the minutes of the Executive Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Distributes minutes of the Executive Board meetings within two weeks following each meeting.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officers&amp;rsquo; Election and Term. The Executive Board Officers shall be elected by a majority vote of the Executive Board. The term of office shall be two years, to commence on January 1 with the exception of the first year. An announcement of the newly elected officers will be sent to the membership promptly following the election. Officers may serve consecutive terms with a two-thirds (&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) majority vote of the member libraries, hereafter known as the “membership”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vacancies. A vacancy in the office of the Chair shall be filled by the Vice-chair who will serve until the end of the normal term of the vacated office. A vacancy in other offices will be filled by appointment by the Executive Board.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Removal. A two-thirds (&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) vote of no confidence from the Executive Board will remove any officer from office. Should any officer be removed, the Executive Board can elect a new representative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quorum. A Simple majority of voting members of the Executive Board shall constitute a quorum for the transaction of business at meetings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meetings. The Executive Board shall hold at least four meetings per year, with other meetings scheduled as needed. The general membership shall be notified in advance of all Executive Board meetings. All Executive Board meetings are open to member libraries and other interested parties, but only Executive Board members may vote at Executive Board meetings. Additional meetings can be scheduled in the following circumstances:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the call of the Chair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At the request of two members of the Executive Board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To review all contracts and to make recommendations for approval&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powers. The Executive Board shall:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formulate policies pertaining to COOL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Act upon recommendation pertaining to COOL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make recommendations pertaining to COOL and other related issues, e.g personnel, upgrades, enhancements, support, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct research to determine the best practices at any given time.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Attendance. If an Executive Board member cannot attend an Executive Board meeting, the member may make advance arrangements with the Chair and the hosting site to participate electronically, by conference call, or other technology that allows full member participation, with the understanding that these technologies are not conducive to full transcription of the meeting discussion, and that only minimal transcription of actual motions on the floor may be possible when the question is called.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Voting. Only an Executive Board member or designee may cast a vote at an Executive Board meeting. Decisions of the Executive Board are binding on all member libraries. Decisions will be made by a simple majority of Executive Board members present.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electronic Balloting. At the direction of the Chair of the Executive Board, items may be brought to the Executive Board for electronic ballot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notice of issues for electronic ballot must be electronically mailed to each member of the Executive Board on (1) week prior tot he designated “close of ballot” date.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ballots returned shall be counted if they are dated on or before the designated close of ballot date.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;working-groups&#34;&gt;WORKING GROUPS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appropriate Working Groups (Cataloging, Circulation, Training, etc.) will be recommended and approved by the COOL Executive Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;amendment-to-the-bylaws&#34;&gt;AMENDMENT TO THE BYLAWS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL Bylaws may be amended at any time by a two-thirds (&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;3&lt;/sub&gt;) majority vote of the member libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thirty (30) days prior written notice shall be given to all member libraries of proposed amendments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proposed amendments must be submitted in writing to the Executive Board Chair.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rules-of-order&#34;&gt;RULES OF ORDER&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL meetings shall be governed by Robert&amp;rsquo;s Rules of Order and the laws of the State of Ohio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fiscal-agent&#34;&gt;FISCAL AGENT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OHIONET is the fiscal agent for COOL subject to review and approval by the COOL Executive Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to Release 3.0</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade3-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade3-0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 10, COOL became the first consortium on the Sequoia platform to upgrade to the 3.0 release of Evergreen. New features include the ability to batch edit patron records and the ability to send text message notifications to patrons 3 days prior to the due date of any circulting material. Release 3.0 initiates the transition from the XUL staff client to a web-based staff client for all Evergreen modules, including serials and acquisitions. Library staff will no longer need to download separate software to interact with Evergreen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Consortium of Ohio Libraries contributed funding for the development of the web-based staff client, along with the following organizations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bibliomation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;British Columbia Libraries Cooperative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C/W MARS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Georgia Public Library Service&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grand Rapids Public Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Howe Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kenton County Public Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;King County Library System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MassLNC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NC Cardinal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pennsylvania Integrated Library System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pioneer Library System&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SC LENDS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL Leadership for 2018</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/elections2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/elections2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elections were held during the December meeting of the COOL Directors. Congratulations to our new leaders!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meme Marlow, Worch Memorial Public Library, Chair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joe Knueven, Germantown Public Library, Vice Chair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kathleen Webb, Marvin Memorial Public Library, Secretary&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RightClick 2017</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/rightclick2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/rightclick2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two representatives from the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, Joe Knueven, Director of Germantown Public Library, and Derek Zoladz, Project Coordinator for the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, will be speaking at RightClick: The Library IT Idea Exchange Conference. Sponsored by the Ohio Library Councel&amp;rsquo;s Information Technology Division, this one-day conference for IT professionals, administrators and support staff will be held at the State Library of Ohio in downtown Columbus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the summaries for each presentation. We&amp;rsquo;ll see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beam me up, Scotty: Migrating into an Evergreen Consortium&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/dzoladz/rightclick2017&#34;&gt;Presentation Slides &amp;amp; Repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you considered migrating to an open source ILS, but are unsure of the process? Migrating to a new ILS is a considerable undertaking, but the first step is to know what’s involved. Gain a better understanding of the framework for ILS migration including key considerations related to Evergreen. You will leave this session equipped with the information you need to continue exploring open source ILS migrations independently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Open Source? The Struggle Between Time, Money and Brains&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the open source software at the Germantown Public Library, as well as some of the reasoning and rationale used in choosing software installations, and how the process has led to a preference for free open source software (FOSS).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technology</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/technology/technology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/technology/technology/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The Consortium of Ohio Libraries integrates a broad spectrum of open source technology to support day-to-day library operations, while collaborating with a carefully curated set of technology partners to provide a superior quality of service to our growing library community.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;evergreen-ils-https-evergreen-ils-org&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://evergreen-ils.org/&#34;&gt;Evergreen ILS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evergreen is a highly-scalable, fully-featured open source ILS that is currently used by over 2,000 libraries both in the US and internationally, with an active and growing community of developers and users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;libki-http-libki-org&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://libki.org/&#34;&gt;Libki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libki is a cross-platform open source computer reservation &amp;amp; time management system with the ability to provide single sign-on authentication with a SIP2-compliant ILS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;libreoffice-https-www-libreoffice-org&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.libreoffice.org&#34;&gt;LibreOffice&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LibreOffice is an open source, feature-complete office productivity suite. LibreOffice utilizes the OpenDocument Text format, a preservation-quality ISO standardized format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;concrete5-https-www-concrete5-org&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.concrete5.org&#34;&gt;concrete5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;concrete5 is an open source content management system designed for rapid development of web content with intuitive controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;screenly-ose-https-www-screenly-io-ose&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.screenly.io/ose&#34;&gt;Screenly OSE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open source, digital signage solution that is designed to run on lightweight hardware such as the Raspberry Pi. Screenly OSE can be used to inform patrons of new services, provide programming announcements, or display the day&amp;rsquo;s event schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;etcher-https-etcher-io&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://etcher.io&#34;&gt;Etcher&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etcher is a dependable, open source utility for flashing operating system images to an SDCard or USB drive&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EIC 2017</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/eic-2017/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Greater Cincinnati area, namely, Covington, KY, has been selected as the location for the 2017 Evergreen International Conference. The proposal was developed by Joe Knueven, director of the Germantown Public Library, and is a multi-state collaborative effort including the Consortium of Ohio Libraries, Asbury Theological Seminary (KY), Asbury University (KY), Kenton County Public Library (KY), and Evergreen Indiana. Knueven has also been named chair of the conference committee and will oversee the planning and implementation of the event. For more information about the Evergreen ILS, visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://evergreen-ils.org&#34;&gt;http://evergreen-ils.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floating in the Most Peculiar Way</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/floating/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/floating/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago, COOL started floating collections between independently governed and funded libraries. The goal is to reduce wait times for patrons at member libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s how it works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL libraries purchase multiple copies of items with high hold/copy ratios.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items are processed without any local branding.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Items circulate throughout the consortium, without any geographic restrictions, on a “first in, first out” basis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once hold lists are fulfilled, the item resides where it was last returned and remains there until a hold from another library is generated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looking at circulation numbers, it appears it is working as intended. Items with more than five holds per copy have reduced 12% since the project started. We only expect it to continue to improve as time goes on.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Joe Knueven, director of Germantown Public Library and Chauncey Montgomery, director of Community Library (Sunbury) will be doing a in-depth presentation of the project at the 2016 EIC conference in Raleigh, NC.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Authority Anyone?</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/authority/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2015 13:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/authority/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest factors in having a successful catalog for your library or consortium is having good records!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind, COOL has very recently partnered with Backstage Library Works (BSLW) and has instituted ongoing authority control for the catalog/database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/img/auth_control.png&#34; alt=&#34;image of a record&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ongoing, we will be loading both updated bibliographic records as well as authority records in an ongoing quarterly process.  At the same time, we’re instituting manual authority control procedures for locally created and eBook records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s certainly never easy, the end result will be a better catalog for both our patrons and staff!  If you have any questions for your library, drop us a line–we’ll be glad to help!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move to Sequoia</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/sequoia/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/sequoia/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On January 13, COOL moved to Sequoia. For more information, visit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://esilibrary.com/what-we-do/sequoia&#34;&gt;http://esilibrary.com/what-we-do/sequoia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade to 2.7</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade2-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/upgrade2-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COOL will be upgrading to Evergreen 2.7 this December. The 2.7 version includes a Web-based staff interface that allows staff to turn any device with Internet access and a Web browser into a staff client. We will be able to perform circulation almost anywhere we need to with little effort.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles of Cooperation</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/policy/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2014 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/policy/principles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL will have a union catalog&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL will have a combined patron database. All libraries will be able to update patron information from all other libraries to make keeping up with new contact information easier.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL libraries will update patron information annually to keep current contact information.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL libraries will contribute the expertise of their staff in IT, cataloging, training, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL libraries will keep their own library cards, but the barcodes will be recognized in all consortium libraries. Patrons shall be limited to one account per person.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patrons in good standing with their home library can borrow from the consortium. Patrons above the fine or overdue limit within their home library system will be blocked from borrowing from all COOL libraries regardless of the fine or overdue limits of the other library systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fines and fees can only be waived by the home library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Libraries will use the statewide resource sharing delivery system and pay for contracted delivery costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL libraries must use the designated cataloging arrangement set by the Executive Board.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consortium borrowing.

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL patrons can borrow and return items to any COOL library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;COOL libraries will share any circulating resource, with the exception of realia, with any COOL library, and allow item age restrictions on new materials for up to three months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The borrowing library is responsible for the circulation, retrieval, and return of borrowed items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The borrowing library’s fines and fees policies will apply to any item checked out through that library, regardless of where the item comes from. Fines collected will not be transferred between libraries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The lending library will absorb the cost of any lost or damaged materials.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing reciprocal borrowing agreements with libraries outside COOL will still be in force; however, patrons of those libraries will not be able to borrow items through COOL unless they have an account at a COOL library.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Libraries will process COOL requests daily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Loan periods, including renewals, will conform to the borrowing library’s lending policies and will not exceed three months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Living in Ohio</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/ohio/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/ohio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What makes Ohio such a great state to live in?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out number eight:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.movoto.com/oh/only-people-from-ohio-understand/&#34;&gt;http://www.movoto.com/oh/only-people-from-ohio-understand/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Boston!</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COOL members just returned from the 2014 Evergreen International Conference in Boston. It was such a great event. We built relationships with Evergreen users from all over the world, we discussed upcoming software features, and we improved our knowledge of the software. COOL also co-presented a tutorial on reporting and participated in a welcome panel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/img/eic2014.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Evergreen Conference 2014&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Events like this reiterate that Evergreen is more than just an ILS; it is a community of librarians, developers, etc., working together to build the best library experience ever. We’re all looking forward to the 2015 EIC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about Evergreen or COOL, please contact Lisa Murray at lmurray@cardlinc.org or Chauncey Montgomery at chauncey@yourcl.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome Marvin</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/marvin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/marvin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;COOL would like to welcome Marvin Memorial Public Library in Shelby to COOL-CAT. On February 20, Marvin Memorial went live, bringing the total membership to eleven libraries with approximately 580,000 items in the system. To see a full list of members and a map of locations, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://info.cool-cat.org/#member-libraries&#34;&gt;http://info.cool-cat.org/#member-libraries&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL is running on Evergreen, the open source ILS, and is supported by OHIONET out of Columbus, Ohio. If you have any questions about Evergreen or joining COOL, please feel free to contact Lisa Murray, consortium chair at 419-864-8181 or lmurray@cardlinc.org.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COOL in Boston</title>
      <link>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/post/boston/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dzoladz.github.io/cool-info/img/econ2014.gif&#34; alt=&#34;Conference logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;COOL will be representing Ohio libraries in two presentations at the 2014 Evergreen International Conference in Boston this March. One session is a tutorial on reports in Evergreen and the second is a panel discussion on migrating to Evergreen. To see a full list of programs, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://evergreen-ils.org/conference/eg14/schedule/&#34;&gt;http://evergreen-ils.org/conference/eg14/schedule/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
